Opening~!
Break~!
The Rain’s Gift
The precious bottle I received for passing Ioryogi-san’s test.
When this is filled, my wish will come true and I’ll be able to go to the place I want to. Right, Ioryogi-san?
I wonder when it will be filled?
We are looking forward to it, right, Ioryogi-san?
You know…
…you are the one who should fill it up, right?
Hanato Kobato!
Yes!
So far you only have the bottle. Nothing’s started yet.
What are you collecting in that bottle?
Yes! I’m collecting people’s broken hearts, Ioryogi-san.
What do you need to do to collect them?
Yes! I need to heal those broken hearts!
All right. It seems you understand.
Now you’d better start collecting!
Yes!
Oh, I forgot to mention something.
When you’re with a human, do not talk to me.
Huh? Why is that?
You’re not the sharpest tool in the shed, so I’ll tell you.
Stuffed animals don’t usually talk, and if you talk to inanimate objects, you’ll look strange. Got it?
Ah, why don’t they talk?
Because they’re stuffed animals.
But why don’t they talk?
Just hurry up and go!
Yes! I’ll do my best!
Don’t get off the see-saw so suddenly!
Is anyone here feeling hurt?
Does anyone here want to be healed?
Isn’t there anyone here who feels hurt?
Please let me heal your heart.
Eh, I’m in a hurry.
Excuse me. Isn’t there any way I can be of service?
Hey.
Isn’t there anything I can help with?
Rock, paper, scissors! Tie-
Miss, please help us.
Eh, what is it?
We need someone to be “it” for Kick the Can.
It?
If I’m “it”, will I be helping you?
Yup! Please!
Okay! I’ll do my best!
I kicked the can!
Yay!
Eh, that’s strange. There’s still nothing in it.
What are you helping by playing Kick the Can?
You aren’t helping anyone by doing stuff like that.
Really?
You’re just being a playmate.
Meeting someone by chance who needs healing is really hard, isn’t it?
But if there’s no one who needs healing, then nobody’s hurt or sad, and that’s a good thing.
Quite the little optimist, aren’t you?
I think finding a way to help
someone out would be good, but…
U-Um…
G-Go ahead.
Is this… for me?
Yes, please.
Handing out such wonderful things without hesitation…
What a wonderful person!
Hey.
I still have all these to hand out,
so if you could take as many as you want, it’d really help me out.
Really?!
Then I’ll take them all!
What?
Thanks! You sure saved me!
I really helped him and now I’ve got all of these wonderful things!
But what are you going to do with all of those?
Now, it’s my turn to hand these wonderful things out.
Huh?
Please have one of these wonderful tissues.
These are very handy, so please help yourselves!
Please.
I’ll give you lots.
I-I’m in a hurry.
Please, these are for you.
Please, help yourselves.
Wonderful tissues. Help yourselves!
That hurt!
I-I’m sorry.
Hey!
Yes!
Don’t loiter in the middle of the street.
I’m sorry.
That person… from before…
Pick up the tissues.
Please wait!
Let me thank you!
I’m sure he went this way…
The sheet flew!
Sayaka-sensei, over here.
What are you doing?
Oh no.
Are you okay?
Yes…
Your nose got scraped.
Huh?
It’s true!
This is so embarrassing.
It’s rude to laugh at her.
Yes, Sayaka-sensei!
I’m sorry. I work here at Yomogi Preschool.
We’re short-handed, so I was bringing in the laundry late.
Oh!
You’re short-handed?
Y-Yes.
Is it troublesome?
I-I guess.
Since you’d need a hand, can I help out?
That’s…
Can I help out?!
Ah, yes.
I’ll help!
Huh?
Please, take these.
Thanks!
Hey, what’s your name?
I’m Toshihiko.
I’m Hanato Kobato.
Kobato? That’s a weird name.
Weird name.
Is that so?
Is your father named Obato, then?
No, he isn’t.
Then what’s his name?
What’s his name?
Um…
Hey! What is it?
Hey.
Hey…
What is it?
Don’t you have a father?
Probably not…
We don’t need his name. Let’s play!
Kids, don’t bother her too much.
Yes, Sayaka-sensei.
U-Um, is there anything I can help with?
Just accompanying the kids is helping enough.
Accompanying?
Um…
Kobato-sensei.
Yes?
Play the organ!
Sorry, but I can’t play the organ.
Really?
I’m sorry.
But we can all dance together.
Dance?
Yeah!
Wait!
Kiyokazu-sensei, play the organ!
We’re going to dance with Kobato-sensei.
I don’t think she’s a teacher.
Well then, Kobato-chan!
What do you think you’ll accomplish by following people around?
I just wanted to thank you.
It’s okay. Go home.
But I said I’d help out!
You can’t play the organ.
Huh?
You’re useless.
Eh? Are you two friends?
No, we’re not!
Oh, is that so?
This is Fujimoto Kiyokazu-kun, whom I work with.
This is Kobato-chan. I’m counting on you today.
Yes!
Don’t get in the way.
Kiyokazu-sensei! Hurry and play the organ!
Sensei! Quickly!
I’m counting on you two.
Dance, Kobato-chan.
What’s that?
T-This person is so unkind. But I’m not giving in!
Kobato-chan’s so funny!
So weird.
Is this a place where children live?
They don’t live here, but we do look after them in the afternoons.
Really?
But this place is really worn-down.
A new preschool just opened, so fewer kids come here now.
But, we need to do our best!
Anyway, it’s useless to worry about it.
Yup! You’re right about that.
Thank you. You really helped us and the kids looked like they had fun.
I-It was nothing. I only played with them.
It always makes Ioryogi-san mad.
Ah!
Oh no! Ioryogi-san isn’t here.
There was someone with you?
Yes. He’s not really someone, but rather, a stuffed animal.
He can’t talk, so if I don’t go get him, he’ll be mad.
Excuse me.
May I come back again tomorrow?
If you could…
Sayaka-sensei.
We don’t know where she lives or what she’s doing here.
Is it really okay for her to be here?
It’s not like that! I’m Hanato Kobato!
All we know is your name. That’s all you ever say.
I’m…
What is it?
I’ve been searching for many things.
Well…
If it’s not a problem for Kobato-chan, we gladly accept it.
It’s just that we can’t really give you any money for helping.
That’s okay. I just want to be able to help.
Then we’ll be counting on you.
Hey.
Yes?
Let me tell you one thing.
If you feel sorry for us or are just curious, then don’t come back.
Huh?
It’s a bother having people think you’re pitiable or have it hard.
I don’t think that at all!
Um…
A bother?
It is a bother.
Leaving someone behind in the middle of the city.
Isn’t it great that I found you, Ioryogi-san?
You didn’t!
Do you know how difficult it is to try to move amongst people, little by little, while they’re staring at you?!
I’m sorry!
I thought I told you! I’m a stuffed animal here!
Stuffed animals can’t just walk around!
I’m so sorry!
You get the bottle and then just forget about me!
The bottle!
Just as I thought…
What do you mean? You thought something would be in there?
I guess the things I’m doing aren’t healing anyone.
Instead, I wonder if I’m just a bother…
It seems like something is hurting Fujimoto-san.
But he said I was bothersome.
Everybody thinks that.
In this world, there are those who are hurt and those who aren’t.
Among those who are hurt are those who wish to be healed and those who don’t.
I didn’t know that.
So what?
Excuse me?
What do you want to do?
I…
If you want to heal them, then just do it.
Is that really okay?
Good or bad, it doesn’t matter. You just need to think about healing them.
Yes!
See you later.
See you.
See you tomorrow.
Bye-bye!
We have to hurry home.
That’s…
Toshihiko-kun?
Kobato-chan.
What about preschool? Are you going home now?
Yeah, but not yet…
Huh?
Do you like the swings?
Not that much. But I’ll stay here a little longer until Mom gets back home.
It’s her job, after all.
Her job, huh?
But…
…she’s trying really hard!
The divorce was tough, but she still makes breakfast for me.
She’s nice. Really!
That’s amazing!
Huh?
You’re not gonna say it? That it’s bad…
What is?
Toshihiko-kun, your mother’s not coming to pick you up today?
No…
Oh… you’re so understanding and unselfish.
Today too? You’re so good to be waiting patiently.
It’d be nice if your mother would think about you a little more.
Yeah.
How much work can she have? It really is bad parenting, isn’t it?
Everyone says I have a bad mom, and that what she’s doing is wrong.
What she’s doing is wrong?
No! She’s trying her hardest!
Really! She’s really great!
That’s wonderful.
A mother who tries her best is wonderful.
Really?
Yes! She’s a wonderful mother!
W-What’s wrong?
Does it hurt somewhere?
That’s not it.
Really?
Uh huh.
Eh!
T-There’s something inside, but what is it?
It’s from that Toshihiko kid.
Toshihiko-kun?
Look, look!
Keep trying, Kobato-chan.
Toshihiko-kun, you’re too good.
If you don’t push harder…
He was happy that you said nice things about his mother.
I was nice? Me?
You will never heal anybody if you’re
insincere, even if you are nice about it.
It’s okay to do what you want to do.
Yes!
I’ll do my best collecting people’s broken hearts.
Just wait a minute!
It’ll sound like you’re going to break their hearts if you put it that way.
Then, their mended hearts?
That sounds like you’re going to take them away.
What should we call it then?
Argh, what a pain!
That looks like confetti candy, so confetti is okay!
Confetti?
I understand! Then let’s call this confetti!
Hey, Kobato!
Yes?
Leaving me behind was inexcusable.
But you were good for your first try.
That’s why I am ignoring it and giving you 100 points.
Go ahead and keep this up
with high spirits, Kobato!
Yes! I’ll do my best.
Even though you got 100 points, don’t get too ahead of yourself.
But you said to go ahead and keep this up!
That’s not what I meant!
Then how do I go ahead?
That’s it! I’m taking your points away!
Ah! No way!